有种东西能够取代传统打字机  知道吗
They have a cure for that, you know?
就是电脑
It's called a computer.
今天就到这儿吗
We done for the day,
或者我要去找些别的书来读
or do I need to find something else to read?
今天就这些
I'm done.
这书写完了
It's done.
不是吧  写完了吗
No way. It's finished?
怎么收尾的
Well, how--how's it end?
你得给我看看
I mean, you got to let me read it.
这次就算了吧
Not this time.
至少你要告诉我发什么了什么事
W--you at least got to tell me what happens.
说呀
Come on.
你不告诉我结局  下一本书  我该怎么做
How am I supposed to help with the next book if you don't--
不会有下一本了
There isn't going to be a next book.
你不是来真的吧  为什么
You can't be serious. Why?
你不会懂的
You wouldn't understand.
试试
Try me.
我只是继续不下去了
I just can't do it anymore.
我不像你那么勇敢
I'm not brave like you.
但写作是你的全部
But writing' your whole life.
不写作  你能去做什么呢
What are you gonna do without it?
做我几年前就该做的事
What I should have done years ago.
你要做什么
What are you doing?
把枪放下  不然我
Put it down, or I'll--
我会逼你放下的
I'll make you.
你怎么做  杰克
How, Jack?
你根本不存在
You don't even exist.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
唐纳小姐
Miss Tanner.
上帝啊
Oh, dear god.
字幕
??
哪个更代表  我想和你上床
Which of these says "I want to sleep with you" more?
企鹅  还是海狸
Penguin or beaver?
海狸  海狸  海狸
Beaver. Beaver. Beaver.
你是对的  太幼稚了
You're right. It's too high school.
你又惹卡迪生气了吗
What did you do to piss Cuddy off?
我不能浪漫点吗
I can't be romantic?
豪斯  你要偷一个陷入昏迷的女人的东西
House, you're stealing from a woman in a coma.
没事  没见过她比现在更开心的
We're fine. Never seen her happier.
是吗  那你呢
Yeah? How about you?
我...很担心
I'm...worried.
因为她开心吗
Because she's happy?
不  因为我开心了
No, because I am.
豪斯  这
House, that's--
很讽刺吗  诡异还是疯狂呢
Ironic? Weird? Crazy?
我是想说这很正常
I was going to say normal.
眼下是这样
For now.
我们还处于热恋阶段
We're in the honeymoon period.
我们的大脑充满了内啡肽
Our brains are flooded with endorphins.
一旦她不受其影响
Once she snaps out of it,
我们会发生什么呢
where does that leave us?
成人恋爱关系
In an adult relationship.
除了工作之外  说说我和卡迪的一个共同点
Name one thing that Cuddy and I have in common besides work.
这...
There's...
你们两个都...
You're both...
等下
Wait.
的确没有共同点
Exactly.
长期关系要能容忍对方
Long-term relationships are based on compatibility,
目前为止  只有做爱符合要求
And right now we only have sex.
豪斯  难道你真以为
House, you don't actually think
她会因为你不做瑜伽之类的事
she'd dump you because you, what,
而甩了你吗
don't do yoga?
还是因为你喜欢听B-52的起飞声音
Listen to the B-52s?
没那么快
Not right away.
我们会吵架  用做爱来弥补
We'll fight, makeup sex,
然后吵架  也许还会做爱
Fight, maybe sex,
直到她甩了我
And then she'll dump me.
也许还会来次告别做爱
With possible goodbye sex.
也就是说  你没有享受热恋阶段
So, instead of enjoying the honeymoon phase,
决定直接跳过去
You've decided to skip it entirely.
我需要找些在一起的时候
I need to find something that we both like doing
我们都喜欢的事情
besides each other.
对  或者你可以直接和她谈谈
Right. Or you could just talk to her about it.
不  那样的话她会装作喜欢那些
No, then she'll start pretending to like things
她原本不喜欢的事  让我好过
that she really doesn't just to make me feel better,
这会让她觉得更糟
which will make her feel even worse,
这不是我的错  所以我会对她不满
which won't be my fault, so I'll resent her,
这也不是她的错  所以她会对我不满
and that won't be her fault, so she'll resent me.
至少实施我的计划
At least with my plan
会让我过着讽刺的一天  直到欢喜收场
I get my one a day with iron till the bitter end.
你跟着我有什么理由吗
Is there a reason why you're following me?
是的
Oh, yeah.
刚刚有人来看急诊  说出来是谁你肯定不信
You're not gonna believe who just checked into the ER.
医生还没有为你做检查
The doctor hasn't examined you yet.
我没事
There's nothing wrong with me.
我的佣人反应过大了
My maid just overreacted.
太好了
Great.
不会占用你太长时间
This won't take long then.
急诊医生发现她昏迷不醒
EMTs found her unconscious.
她的佣人说她发生了癫痫
Her maid said she had a seizure.
我昏过去了
I fainted.
顺便说下  我是杰克·加农超级粉丝
Huge Jack Cannon fan, by the way.
我喜欢你的书
Love your books.
真的吗
Really?
我的书迷一般都是十多岁的吵闹小女孩
My fans tend to be overly-annoying teenaged girls.
我知道
I know.
她们就只在乎谁更帅一些
All they care about is who's hotter,
杰克还是迪肯
Jack or Deacon.
就像萨拉无法两者都爱一样
Like Sarah can't love both of them.
我可能是一两个在线书迷俱乐部的会员
I may belong to one or two online fan clubs.
新书进展如何
How's the new book coming along?
我不讨论自己的作品
I don't talk about my work.
好的
Okay.
点头回答我几个
How about nodding your head
是非问题怎么样
to a few yes/no questions?
但我可以跟你做笔交易
But I'll make you a deal.
你快点完成检查
You finish this exam quickly,
我回答你一个问题
and I'll answer one question.
任何问题都可以
About anything?
任何都可以
Anything.
谁是杰克的亲生父亲
Who was Jack's real father,
谁绑架了他叔叔之类
who kidnapped his uncle...
成交
Deal.
我更想知道
I will have to go with
你为什么要自杀
why'd you try to kill yourself?
你侧脸的灼伤
Burn on the side of your face
是火药留下的
is caused by gunpowder,
你是最后一刻改变想法了呢
So change your mind at the last second,
还是枪法太逊呢
or you just a lousy shot?
我要离开这儿
I'm out of here.
还不能走  我们有笔交易没完成
Can't. We had a deal.
你拦着我试试
Try and stop me.
好的
Okay.
她处于72小时精神监控期
This woman is on a 72-hour psychiatric hold.
如果她想逃跑就向她开枪
If she tries to run, shoot her.
我指的是用镇静剂
With a sedative.
更方便些
That's more convenient.
你打电话叫我们回来工作
You called us back to work
就因为有位女士发生过癫痫
because a lady might have had a seizure.
是她自杀的时候发生的癫痫
A seizure while trying to commit suicide.
那就送她去做精神诊断
So send her for a psych EVAL.
我们能有什么办法
What's that got to do with us?
你们各位都怎么了
What is the matter with you people?
我们在讨论的是一个被痛苦折磨的人
We're talking about a human being who's suffering.
你们是对的  这些还不够
You're right. That's not enough.
她还是《杰克·加农:少年神探》的作者
She is also the writer of Jack Cannon: Boy Detective,
深受百万书迷的喜爱
beloved by millions around the world.
都是10到14岁的小女孩
By girls between 10 and 14.
关键在于
Look, the point is
如果她自杀了
if she kills herself,
几百万各个年龄和不同性别的书迷
millions of fans of all ages and genders
都会非常失望的
will be very disappointed.
我们讨论这个病例就因为你是她的书迷
So we're taking this case 'cause you're a fan?
不  那样太疯狂了  也不够专业
No, that would be crazy and unprofessional.
因为我让你们讨论这个病例你们才讨论的
You're taking this case 'cause I said so.
和你陶博去做个全面病情检查
You and Taub do a full workup.
通宵观察她
Observe her overnight.
看看她是否会再次发生癫痫  你可以走了
See if she has another seizure. You can go.
为什么他可以休息一晚
Why does he get the night off?
因为他带来一个抽烟的辣妹
Because he brought a smokin' hot babe.
我和妻子有安排的
I have plans with my wife.
嗯  想得很好
Yeah, nice try,
但你讨厌自己的私人生活
But you hate your personal life.
显然你连私人生活都没有
And you obviously don't have one.
喂
Hey.
本来我打算自己留下的
I'd stay myself,
但我刚买好了花
but I just bought the flowers.
多米尼克的预定是在8点以后
Reservation for Dominica's isn't till 8:00,
所以我们有的是时间
so we got plenty of time.
我们要从闹鬼的房子里找什么东西
We need to pick something up from a haunted house?
这是哥特式建筑复兴的杰作
This is a Gothic revival masterpiece.
我希望有一天能住在这样的房子里
I hope one day to live in a house like this.
你朋友是作家吗
Your friend's a writer?
最好的作家之一
One of the best.
她希望我读一读她的最新手稿
She wants me to read her latest manuscript.
爱丽丝·唐纳
Alice Tanner.
为什么这名字听起来耳熟
Why does that name sound familiar?
几年前  我给了你几本她写的书
I gave you a couple of her books a few years ago.
不对
No.
她是你送去精神监控那个人
She's the woman you put on the psych hold.
这不是约会
This isn't a date.
我们这是出诊
We're on a case.
有没有听说过多重任务处理
Ever hear of multitasking?
你偷了她的钥匙吗
Did you steal her keys?
你以为我会带着院长入室行窃吗
Think I'd take the dean of medicine on a "B" and "E"?
你们怎么进来的
How did you get in here?
我猜你有了答案了
Well, I guess you have your answer.
你上次体检是什么时候
When was your last physical?
就在刚才
A while ago.
我不喜欢医生
I don't like doctors.
今天之前有癫痫史吗
Any history of seizures before today?
印象中没有
Not that I recall.
检查完了吗
Are we almost done?
我累了
I'm tired.
如果你能配合我们一些
The exam would go faster
检查会快点
if you would cooperate with us.
我在配合
I am.
你回避我们提出的每一给问题
You're evading every question we ask.
为什么这么说
Why do you say that?
正是如此
That.
我可没求你们帮我
I didn't ask for help.
准备好自杀的姿势可不是这个意思啊
Committing a suicidal gesture says otherwise.
那可不是做做样子而已
It wasn't a gesture.
就在我把枪塞到嘴里之前
I had the damn seizure
这该死的癫痫发作了
before I could get the gun in my mouth.
想不想告诉我们原因
You want to tell us why?
你想知道我人生历程吗
You want to know my life story,
我深藏于心的痛苦吗
my secret inner pain?
也许如果我稍微敞开心扉
Maybe if I just open up a little,
你们就能拯救我吗
you'll be able to save me?
我们只是想帮你而已
We're just trying to help you.
谢谢你
Thank you.
我想要女医生
I want a woman doctor.
你又回避问题了
And back to being evasive.
这是我当病人的权利
It's my right as a patient.
所以请你们出去  立刻出去
So please get out. Now.
我们要通宵观察你
We need to observe you overnight.
你们真以为我傻到
You really think I'm stupid enough
在医院自杀吗
to try and kill myself in a hospital?
是看你会不会再次发作癫痫
To see if you have another seizure.
我们会在那边守着
We'll be up there,
除非有情况  不然不会打扰你
and we won't disturb you unless there's a problem.
你看这样可以吗
That work for you?
只要你们离开这儿就可以
Whatever it takes to get you out of here.
豪斯  克里斯蒂娜同意不通知警方
House, Christina has agreed to not call the police.
她很可能是非法移民
She's probably illegal.
这也是她不上报自杀的原因
Same reason she didn't report the suicide attempt.
我拨了911
I call 911.
但唐纳小姐醒来的时候
But when Miss Tanner woke up,
她说如果我提到枪的事
she say she will fire me
她就解雇我
if I say anything about the gun.
如果她了结了自己  你还能有工作吗
And if she whacks herself, what happens to your job?
我觉得她是个情绪非常低落的人
I think she's a very depressed person.
她从不出门
Never goes out,
也没有朋友
doesn't have friends.
她有很多钱
She has all this money,
但她只是写作
but all she does is write.
我要看看她最新的手稿
I need to see her latest manuscript.
她一直都把成稿锁在那儿
She always locks up her writing in there.
她抱怨过
Has she ever complained
身体方面的疼痛或者压力吗
about physical pain or stress?
是的
Yes.
她的背和手疼得厉害
Her back and her hands hurt a lot.
一个背和手疼的作家
A writer with back and hand pain.
非常有帮助  我们走吧
That's very helpful. Let's go.
有时候我在夜里听到她哭
Sometimes I hear her cry at night.
她以为这时候没人能听到
When she thinks nobody's listening.
我本该做些什么的
I should have done something.
没错
True.
你在做什么
What are you doing?
在硬盘发明之前
Before there were hard drives,
我们用的是
there were...
这东西她每天吃几盒
How many of these does she eat a day?
午饭吃两盒
Two for lunch.
有时吃三盒
Sometimes three.
没有癫痫的现象
Still no seizure activity.
轮到你了
It's your turn--
怎么了
What the hell?
凑近点看  是豪斯
Close. House.
她很好
She's fine.
她的脑电图和全部生命体征都
Both the EEG and all her vitals have been--
是你
You.
你想做什么
What do you want?
你尿床了
You wet the bed.
只是还不知道为什么会这样
Just not sure how yet.
早上好  先生们
Good morning, gentlemen.
如果说出来能让你们得到安慰
Well, if it's any consolation,
其实我也没怎么睡
I didn't get any sleep either.
特发性单侧局限性多汗症
Unilateral hyperhidrosis.
有意思
Interesting.
她还承认了她曾经自杀
She also admitted she tried to kill herself,
但是不告诉我们原因
but won't tell us why.
豪斯搜了她家
House searched her home,
发现她几年来每天都吃两盒金枪鱼罐头
found she's been eating two cans of tuna a day for years.
汞中毒
Mercury poisoning?
能够说明癫痫
Explains the seizures,
背部和手疼
hand and back pain,
还有抑郁
also the depression.
除了事实  说明了一切
Explains everything except the fact that it's not.
我们取回了她的尿样和血样
We got her urine and blood samples back.
都是正常的
They're normal.
如果低含量水平
If it's low level,
抽查时就不会发现
it might not show up in a spot check.
我们需要继续测试找出病因
We need to run continuous testing to find it.
没办法了  她要求换成女医生
We can't. She wants a female doctor.
她要求女医生只是在浪费时间而已
She only asked for a woman to waste time.
她配合我们只是想结束精神监控而已
She's cooperating just enough to get through the psych hold.
让奇斯涂上口红  开始螯合疗法
Put some lipstick on Chase and start chelation therapy.
确认另一次尿检
Confirm with another urine test.
好的
Okay.
我和去卡迪谈谈
I'll go talk to Cuddy.
也许她能再借我们一条裙子
Maybe she'll let us borrow a dress, too.
我就是我无视你的时候
This would be me ignoring you.
如果昨晚我们被逮捕了怎么办
What if we got arrested last night?
怎样才能让我们的
And whatever happened to keeping
工作和生活分开呢
our professional and personal lives separate?
我不是工作时间讨论我们私人关系的人
I'm not the one talking about our relationship at work.
你背后藏着什么
What's behind your back?
和平企鹅
Peace penguin.
我要把这还给哪个病房
What room should I return it to?
243号
243.
爱丽丝·唐纳的事我需要你帮忙
I need some help with Alice Tanner.
她需要借一个"女"医生
She wants a vagina.
我和我的女性特征紧密相连
I'm pretty attached to mine.
两周之前
I told you
我就告诉你找个人临时代替十三
to hire a temporary replacement for thirteen two weeks ago.
-我一直在忙  -忙着干吗
- I've been busy. - Doing what?
和你的事
You.
那你来劝她别这样吗
So you'll talk her out of it?
你雇不雇女医生
You'll hire a woman doctor?
莫非你以为没有美妞在旁  我们就会
You think we just sit around talking sports
无所事事  大侃体育  打嗝放屁了
and belching and farting when the chicks aren't around?
时间期限
By when?
下周前
Next week.
那就下周前
Next week it is.
你们为什么认为是汞中毒
What makes you think it's mercury?
你的症状
Your symptoms.
如果你仍坚持要女医生
Now I can perform the procedure yourself
我可以为你治疗
if you still prefer a woman doctor,
但为你工作的团队是最棒的
but the team you have is our best.
你用的香水真有趣
That's an interesting perfume you're wearing.
是礼物
It was a gift.
豪斯医生送的
From Dr. House?
昨晚他身上都是这个味道
It was all over him last night.
如果你想换一位女性医生
If you'd prefer another female doctor,
我也可以安排
I can arrange that as well.
我刚刚还在其他人身上闻到过这个味道
I also smelled it somewhere else more recently.
很淡  但不会错认
Faint, but unmistakable.
克里斯蒂娜  你今早该换一件羊毛衫才是
You should have worn a different cardigan this morning, Christina.
有什么事要告诉我吗  亲爱的
Something you'd like to tell me, dear?
昨天发现你的时候
When I found you yesterday,
我以为已经太迟了
I thought I was too late.
我希望你好起来  所以跟他们谈了
I talked to them so I could help you get better.
我不想再看你受苦
I just don't want to see you suffer anymore.
不会了
That won't be a problem.
你被解雇了
You're fired.
她关心你
This woman cares about you.
如果没有她
If it weren't for her...
我活不到现在  是不是
I wouldn't be here now, would I?
我昨天就该解雇她
I should have done it yesterday.
你正承受着痛苦  我明白
I understand that you're in pain,
但出语伤人不是解决之道
but lashing out isn't the answer.
治疗才是
Treatment is.
我同意
I agree.
把男医生换回来
Send the men back.
至少他们不会天真兮兮  哭天抹泪
At least they're not a bunch of dewy-eyed cry-babies.
拿的什么
What's that?
最新一本杰克·加农小说
It's the new Jack Cannon novel.
有建议吗
Suggestions?
有
Yeah.
放弃吧
Stop.
你这是行不通的
It can't be done.
难怪你从来没治愈过癌症
People wonder why you've never cured cancer.
什么时候拿的  跟卡迪约会前还是约会后
Did you get this before or after your date with Cuddy?
你或许还有一个更明智的时段可以选
Eh, probably would have been a wiser choice.
豪斯  这其实是好事
This is actually good, House.
她在违法
She's committing crimes.
你有何见解
What does that tell you?
近墨者黑  我害人不浅
I'm a horrible influence.
没错
True.
可她依然要接近你
A horrible influence she's reaching out to.
她在寻求同你交流的途径
She's looking for ways to connect.
纯然是自虐  幼稚  疯狂的举动
Sure, they're self-destructive, juvenile, and insane,
可你也自虐  幼稚  疯狂
But so are you.
你们有了共同点
You do have something in common.
你们都在试图挖掘彼此的共通之处
You're both trying to find things you have in common.
而且都没成功
And not finding them.
你看起来不太高兴
You don't look so hot.
想谈谈吗
Want to talk about it?
我们谈心的时光已经过去了
Those days are over.
你刚才在和谁说话
Who were you talking to?
我自己
Myself.
如果你有幻觉
If you're seeing things,
那可能是一种症状
It could be another symptom.
不是
It's not.
只是我的想象而已
It's only in my imagination.
我以虚构人物为生的
I make things up for a living.
还跟虚构人物讲话呢
And talking to them?
这是作家的通病
It's a writer thing.
作家还善于识人
We're also good at reading people.
比如说你
Like you, for instance.
刚刚离婚
Recently divorced.
昨晚和某女春宵一度
You slept with a girl last night.
在她家不在你家
Her place, not yours.
而你八成不会回她电话
You probably won't return her calls.
神了
That...
怎么看出来的
How?
你手指上戴过婚戒  白印还在
The tan line from your former wedding ring.
满身都是烟味
You stink of smoke,
但是牙齿和手指都没有变黄
but no yellow on your fingers or teeth
说明烟是她吸的
means she's the smoker.
烟味说明你不是没洗澡就是没换衣服
And you either didn't shower or change.
不管哪样  都证明是她家
Either way, her place.
看看他
Do him.
我们正在浪费时间
We're wasting time,
这才是她的目的
which is her main goal here.
伸胳膊
Need your arm for this.
你让我想起我前夫
You remind me of my ex-husband.
人不错  只是总是婚外恋
A cute man, but problems in the bedroom department.
根本不挨边
Not even close.
他数次被我捉奸在床
The ones I caught him in.
只要有机会  他就会找外遇
He cheated on me every chance he could.
第一次是跟我最好的朋友
The first time with my best friend.
第二次
The second...
那个混蛋
The bastard.
血压心率急速上升
BP and heart rate are spiking.
一定是对螯合剂过敏
Must be an allergic reaction to the chelation agent.
我还没给她注射呢
I didn't give it to her yet.
疼痛  癫痫  多汗
Pain, seizures, hyperhidrosis,
突发急性高血压
and sudden onset of radically high blood pressure.
她的后续血检和尿检结果回来了
Her continuous blood and urine test came back.
明显不是汞中毒  阴性
It's definitely not mercury poisoning. Clean.
可能是溶血性尿毒症
Could be hemolytic uremic syndrome.
不是  尿中无血也无蛋白质标记
It's not. There weren't any blood or protein markers in her urine, either.
我们刚才还发现她在自言自语
We also caught her talking to herself.
可能是妄想症状
She could be delusional.
她是个隐居的作家
She's a writer and a recluse.
不自言自语才更奇怪
I'd be more surprised if she didn't talk to herself.
打字带玩够了没
You done playing with your ribbon?
她当时在做什么
What was she doing when it happened?
坐在床上
Sitting in bed.
她说交谈对象只是她的想象
She claims it was only in her imagination,
可也难说
but still.
她血压飙升的时候呢
When her BP spiked?
把陶博比作她前夫
Comparing Taub to her ex-husband.
她真的恨她前夫
She really hated the guy.
第一个症状
Her first symptom
出现在她用枪指着自己头的时候
was when she had a gun to her head.
肾上腺素过量可以解释癫痫和血压飙升
Excess adrenaline could explain seizures and skyrocketing BP.
嗜铬细胞瘤
A pheochromocytoma.
做磁共振把它找出来
Get an MRI and find it.
拿着这个好吗
Would you hold this?
我的意思是马上
I meant now.
我有没有说过  我有幽闭恐怖症
Have I mentioned I'm claustrophobic?
我有没有说过  我们不在乎
Have I mentioned we don't care?
怎么回事
What's wrong?
没什么  腿抽筋而已
Nothing. Just a leg cramp.
把她推出去  她腿里有金属
Get her out of here. She's got metal in her leg.
因为一次滑雪事故  她右腿植入三根螺钉
She has three screws in her right leg
她没告诉我们
from a skiing accident she didn't tell us about.
磁共振的磁场将金属螺钉加热至高温
The MRI's magnetic field super heated the metal,
造成三度烧伤
causing third-degree burns.
这些位置的皮肤因体内高温高压裂开
Skin ruptured from internal heat pressure here.
不是我们的错
It's not our fault.
她签过同意书
She signed the consent forms,
否认体内有任何金属
denied there was any metal...
一般情况下我会说出来
Normally I'd say it.
不过或许这样你们才能真正理解
Maybe this way it'll finally sink in.
她想求死
She wants to die.
不要相信她说的任何话
You cannot trust anything she says.
治疗她腿上的软组织损伤
Treating the soft tissue injuries in her leg
就会花掉这一天中的大部分时间
cost us most of the day.
我们还要更换螺钉
We also had to replace the screws.
不用磁共振  找嗜铬细胞瘤可能需要一周之久
And finding a pheochromocytoma without using the MRI could take us a week.
如果她不停止对我们说谎  会更久
Longer, if she doesn't stop lying to us.
她的精神状态监控还剩39小时
Or we could figure out a way to find it
或许我们可以在此期间想出其他方法
in the 39 hours left on her psych hold.
我们需要让她配合
We need to make her cooperate.
我们必须提出她想要的条件
We have to offer her something she wants.
豪斯  她想要自杀
She wants to kill herself, House.
我可以配合
I can work with that.
我想要你写更多的书
I want you to write more books.
我对杰克·加农奇遇的写作已经终结
I'm done writing Jack Cannon's adventures.
等我离开这里之后
And when I get out of here,
我也就终结了
I'll just be done.
别这么说嘛  你这下流姑娘
Now don't you say that, you dirty birdie.
朝自己脑袋开枪 或者扯断一条腿
You know, there are easier ways to go than shooting yourself in the head
可都不是自杀的好方法
or tearing apart a limb.
这里有一个好方法
And this is one of them.
最妙的是  你会飘飘欲仙
The best part, you'll feel so good,
压根注意不到自己死了
you won't even notice you're dead.
你指望我相信
You expect me to believe
你会协助我自杀
you're going to help me kill myself?
洞悉人心的是你
You're the perceptive one.
你来说
You tell me.
为什么
Why?
你不配合  我们就不能及时找到肿瘤
We can't find your tumor in time without your cooperation.
所以我要让你来选
So I'm giving you a choice.
给我们一个治好你的机会
Give us a chance to make you better,
或者把针管随便一扎一推
or stick this anywhere and push.
你为什么在乎我
Why do you care about me?
你以为你读了我的书就了解我了
You think you know me because you read my books?
不
No.
我了解疼痛
I know pain.
你以为自己应付得来
Think you can handle it,
可终有一天你无法忍受
and one day you can't.
无法再忍的时候
When that happens,
你可能找到理由坚持下去  也可能找不到
you either find reasons to go on, or you don't.
我  我再也找不到理由了
I'm... I'm all out of reasons.
暂时而已
Now.
等疼痛消失
When you're pain free,
你会想要活下去重新开始写作的
you're gonna want to live and start writing again.
而且如果我错了
And if I'm wrong,
你也有备选方案可以带走
got a backup plan to take home with you.
好
Okay.
明智之选
Good choice.
如果我是你
If I were you,
不想被收走就把它藏起来
I'd hide that if you want to keep it.
我知道扎哪里最好
I know the perfect place.
宝贝儿  早上好
Morning, sunshine.
你真是个混蛋
You're a real bastard.
你应该选生路的
You were supposed to choose life.
你还是个出色的骗子
You're also an excellent liar.
可以治愈那部分不是骗你
Wasn't lying about the cure.
如果我们找到并且切除
If we find and remove that pesky,
那个分泌肾上腺素的讨厌瘤
adrenaline-secreting tumor,
你就能好起来
you'll get better.
你们最好快点
You better hurry.
明天这个时候  我的律师就能让我出院了
My lawyer will have me out of here this time tomorrow.
没错  说到这个
Yeah, about that,
你昨晚好像是发现并给自己注射了一种
it seems that last night you found and self-administered
你认为可以致命的药物
what you thought was a potentially lethal narcotic.
你的精神状态监控被延长了24小时
Your psych hold has been extended an additional 24 hours.
我知道  真令人颓丧  是不是
I know. Bummer, right?
想知道我新书里写了什么吗
You want to know something about my book?
当然
Sure.
杰克·加农死了
Jack Cannon dies.
我知道
I know.
真令人颓丧  是不是
Bummer, right?
昨晚的正电子发射层析扫描分析好了
We finished analyzing the PET scans from last night.
没有肿瘤的迹象
There's no sign of a tumor.
我们在六处分别采血
We sampled blood from six different areas
寻找肾上腺素高点
looking for any spikes in adrenaline.
结果全是阴性
All of them were negative.
如果她早告诉我们症状
If she told us her symptoms,
疼痛开始的时候从哪里发起
where it hurts, when the pain first started,
我们至少可以有个搜索的范围
We could at least focus on a specific area.
或者可以避开的范围
Or use them to rule areas out.
她不会说真话
She'll only lie.
我们不和她交谈还更好一些
We're better off not even talking to her.
你能让她再自杀一次吗
You think you can get her to try to kill herself again?
我们需要更多时间
We're gonna need more time.
或许有不必问她就能知道病情的办法
There might be a way to get her symptoms without asking her.
作家只写自己了解的东西
If writers write what they know.
你不是说主人公是少年侦探吗
I thought you said it was about a boy detective.
还有他的良师益友  海伦姨妈
And his mentor, aunt Helen,
碰巧与爱丽丝年龄相仿
who happens to be around the same age as Alice.
答案可能就在书里
Answers could be in the book.
很好  那条打字带读完了吗
Great. You finish reading your typewriter ribbon yet?
用超声波查找肿瘤
Look for the tumor with the ultrasound.
我开车从城那边过来就是治疗打字带的
I drove across town to treat a ribbon?
这就是我更喜欢撒谎的原因
That's why I prefer lying.
谎言让你更轻松
It makes things easier.
不论他让你做的是什么  赶快停下
Whatever he has you doing, stop.
你告诉他了
You told him?
我们两个住在一起的
We do live together.
我来他工作的地方自然要告诉他
I generally tell him when I show up at his work.
豪斯说这事关生死
He told me it was a matter of life and death.
的确
It is.
病人试图自杀
Patient wants to kill herself.
他是在试图读小说
He's just trying to read a book,
最新一部《杰克·加农:少年侦探》
the latest Jack Cannon: boy detective.
爱丽丝·唐纳是你的病人吗
Alice Tanner is your patient?
你也是坎粉吗
You're a "Fannon" Too?
我支持迪肯
I'm team Deacon.
不是吧
Oh, come on.
她就不能两个都爱么
Why can't she love them both?
打字机应该在打字带上留下了印迹
The typewriter keys should have left impressions on these ribbon fibers.
而且也会磨掉一层墨
They would also remove a layer of ink.
只要调调软件就好  简单
It's just a question of tweaking the software, really.
卡迪知道你在用磁共振做这个吗
Does Cuddy know you're using the MRI for this?
就当她知道
Let's say yes.
你觉得这本书里杰克会和萨拉好上吗
So do you think Jack finally hooks up with Sarah in this one?
不会  黛比·赖特才是他的真爱
No. Debbie Wright is his true love.
-她死了  -推测而已
- She's dead. - Presumed!
我们能确知的只不过
All we really know is...
有真正的病人等着用磁共振呢
There are actual patients waiting to use this machine.
恭喜
Congratulations.
书出来了
It's a book.
威尔森刚跟我说  他和山姆
Wilson just told me we're going on a double date
今晚跟我们出去四人约会
with him and Sam tonight.
你不喜欢四人约会吗
You don't like double dates?
我喜欢你事先问问我
I'd just like if you'd ask me first.
你不喜欢惊喜吗
You don't like surprises?
这是爱丽丝的书吗
Is this Alice's book?
山姆重编程磁共振  读出了爱丽丝的打字带
Sam reprogrammed the MRI to read Alice's typewriter ribbon.
你动用了一台价值三百万美元的医疗设备
You used a $3 million piece of hospital equipment
就为了读小说
so you could read a novel?
帅呆了  是不是
Cool, right?
作为你女友的我  由衷折服
Well, as your girlfriend, I'm impressed.
作为你上司的我  认为你是个浑球
As your boss, you're a jackass.
以后别这么干了
Don't do it again.
作为你男友的我  感谢你
As your boyfriend, I thank you.
作为你下属的我  鄙视你
As your employee, I resent you,
因为这是病例需要
because I need this for my case.
作为你上司的我  要你下周多看六小时门诊
As your boss, you just got six more clinic hours next week.
今晚怎么安排
So what's the plan for tonight?
-你想去哪儿都行  -我不在乎
- Whatever you want. - I don't care.
挑一个我俩都喜欢的就好
Just pick something we'd both enjoy.
我们都喜欢什么呢
Yeah? And what would that be exactly?
我说不好  你知道我的喜好
I don't know. You know what I like.
我得回去工作了
I got to get back to work.
有发现
Found something.
不是肿瘤
It's not a tumor.
不知是什么  包裹在心周
Whatever it is, it's encased around her heart.
她心包渗液
She has a pericardial effusion.
昨晚做正电子发射层析扫描时
Which wasn't there last night
还没有出现
when we did the PET scan.
她的病情在恶化
She's getting worse,
但不是嗜铬细胞瘤
and there's no sign of a pheochromocytoma.
癫痫  盗汗  血压快速上升
Seizures, sweating, rapid blood pressure,
以及某种病毒引起的心包积液
and an effusion point to something viral.
也可能是癌症引起的
Or maybe a cancer.
豪斯  我们需要你的意见
We could use your opinion, House,
至少听听我们的说法
or at least your attention.
杰克·加农没有死
Jack Cannon is not dead.
这更糟
It's worse.
写了十本书  结局是最终对决
Ten books leading up to a final confrontation.
掉人胃口
She ends it on a cliffhanger.
谁会干这种事
I mean, who does that?
想卖给你第十一本书的人
People who want to sell you the 11th.
她想自杀
She was gonna kill herself.
没有第十一本杰克·加农了
This is the final Jack Cannon.
什么答案都没有
Nothing gets resolved.
他爸是谁  他兄弟是谁杀的
Who's his father? Who killed his brother?
他脸上的疤是怎么来的
How'd he get that damn scar on his cheek,
他为什么喜欢玩溜溜球
and why is he obsessed with yo-yos?
书里的内容和我们的案子有关系吗
Is there anything in it that pertains to our case?
当然有
Yeah.
我知道她为什么要自杀
I know why she wanted to kill herself.
海伦·拉瑟福德  他的导师
His mentor, Helen Rutherford,
身患重病
has contracted a serious illness
包括关节疼痛
which consists of joint paint,
疲劳  感光灵敏
fatigue, sensitivity to light,
还有抑郁症
and depression.
我们怎么知道导师就是爱丽丝的真实写照
How do we know this mentor character's really Alice?
在这本书中海伦死了
Helen dies halfway through the book.
她崩了自己的脑袋
Shoots herself in the head...
好不成为杰克的累赘
to save Jack from having to care for her.
如果把这些和我们观察到的症状联系在一起
If we add those to the symptoms we've seen
加上心包积液  这是红斑狼疮
and the pericardial effusion...it's lupus.
不可能是红斑狼疮
Can't be lupus.
为什么
Why not?
那是绝症
It isn't curable.
你还是没有解释原因
That's...not an answer.
这病是可以治疗的
It's treatable.
我们会开始测试
We'll start testing to see which drugs
看哪种药对她最有效
she best responds to.
我们没办法带走她的疼痛
We're not gonna be able to take her pain away.
一旦她明天离开这里
She's still gonna kill herself
她还是会自杀
as soon as she gets released tomorrow.
我不能让杰克·加农的故事就这么完了
Can't let Jack Cannon end this way.
我们在医治病人  不是小说
We're treating a patient... not a book.
重新测试以确诊
Retest to confirm.
卡丁车  你认真的吗
Go-carts? Really?
威尔森  四位  下一轮  请准备
Wilson, party of four. You guys are up next.
你妈妈说你喜欢卡丁车
Your mom said you loved go-carts.
你给我妈打过电话了
You called my mother.
我12岁的时候才喜欢玩卡丁车
I loved them when I was 12.
这太棒了
This is so cool!
12岁以后我就没再玩过了
I haven't done this since I was 12!
赢家有权挑饭店
Winner picks the restaurant.
对此我有不好的预感
I have a very bad feeling about this.
准备好了吗  赛车手们
Are we ready, racers?
各就各位
On your marks,
预备
get set...
开始
and go away.
喂  看着点
Hey! Watch it!
开心吗
You having fun?
知道谁会赢吗
You know who wins these races?
份量轻的人
The person who weighs less!
我父母从来不让我玩这种东西
My parents never let me drive one of these!
是啊  我看得出来
Yeah! I can tell!
上帝
Oh, my god!
可怜
Whoa.
她干什么呢
What is her problem?
她讨厌犹太人
She hates jews!
她以后不敢了
Never...again.
我喜欢
That a girl!
唔喔哇哈哈[大王驾到]
Hoo hoo hah hah hah!
终点线等你
See you at the finish line!
是吗
Oh, yeah?
第一名
Yes!
听好了
Hey!
你被终生禁赛了  先生
You're banned for life, mister!
你无权再次参加游戏
Your fun stop privileges are officially revoked!
你也是  金发美女  你们都给我出去
You, too, blondie! All of you--get out!
我为我女朋友报仇了
I avenged my lady.
安全带差点没把我脖子弄断
Seatbelt nearly broke my neck.
我要回去休息了
I'm done for the night.
这不怨我  威尔森就爱疯女人
It's not my fault Wilson's attracted to psychos.
地方是你选的
You picked the place.
那都是气话
That's just the pain talking.
我怎么没想到
Oh...wow.
你的伤是车祸造成的
It was a car crash.
不是滑雪意外
Not a skiing accident.
你说什么
What?
你的腿伤是车祸造成的
Screws in your leg.
你答对了
Ya got me.
我现在要接着睡了
I'll be going back to sleep now.
车祸中肩带切进你的脖子
You damaged your thyroid gland in the crash
破坏了甲状腺
when the shoulder strap cut into your neck.
你没得红斑狼疮
You don't have lupus.
我们可以治好你的病
What you have is curable.
走开
Go away.
我看过你的书了
I read your book.
告诉你  糟透了
Sucks, by the way.
得了吧  你不可能看过
Nice try, but impossible.
海伦·拉瑟福德自杀身亡
Helen Rutherford kills herself
因为她自感无用
because she feels useless
同时她不想成为
and doesn't want to be a burd--
跟你现在的情形一样
Just like you do now.
你只是甲状腺机能减退
You have hypothyroidism.
所以你才疲惫不堪
That's why you feel so tired and worn out.
接受药物治疗能让你感觉年轻20岁
With medication, you'll feel 20 years younger.
或者是回到
Or whatever age you were
你不想自杀时候的年龄
the last time you didn't want to kill yourself.
-你是怎么  -你应该给故事写个结尾
- How did you... - You can finish the story the right way...
杰克·加农应有的结局
the way Jack Cannon deserves.
你以为杰克该有怎样的结局
You think you know what Jack deserves?
我知道至少该比你给他安排的要好
I know that he deserves better than what you gave him.
你一点都不了解他
You don't know anything about him!
你为什么就不能让我
Why can't you just leave me--
你对我做了什么
What did you do to me?
我动不了了
I can't move.
哪里都动不了
I can't move anything.
我怎么会半对半错呢
How can I be right and wrong?
我推断出是车祸
I deduced the car accident
因为甲状腺能解释症状
because thyroid fit the symptoms.
但甲状腺受损不能解释瘫痪
But a damaged thyroid wouldn't explain the paralysis.
我怎么会猜错病因
How can I be wrong about the thyroid
却答对祸根呢
but right about the accident?
如果不是甲状腺呢
What if you're not?
很高兴你能这么想  孩子
I like the way you think, kid.
至少不全是甲状腺的原因
At least not completely.
可能是15年前的车祸造成的创伤后脊髓空洞症
Post traumatic syringomyelia from a 15-year-old car crash.
多年来逐渐形成病灶
Slowly growing over the years,
压迫脊柱
pressing against her spinal column.
会引起疼痛  血压不稳以及癫痫
Causes pain, fluctuating blood pressure, seizures.
如果未得到治疗
And if untreated,
最终将导致瘫痪死亡
eventually leads to paralysis and death.
我们找到病灶进行治疗
We find it and remove it.
系统功能应该能恢复
She should be able to regain full function.
如果我们能拿到她当时的医疗记录
If we can get her medical records from back then,
就能确定病灶的位置
we can use them to pinpoint the location.
去找记录
Do it.
我们已经筋疲力尽了
We're dead on our feet.
我差不多四天没睡了
I've barely slept in four days.
真可怜
Aw...that's sad.
你知道还有什么比这更糟的吗
You know what's even sadder?
十三才是我手下唯一一个男人
Thirteen was the only man on my team.
是啊  你得抓紧雇人
Yeah, it'd be nice if you hurry up
顶上她的空位
and hire someone to fill her spot.
那就去招人
Do it.
卡迪要个女的
Cuddy wants it to be a girl.
是有些人
There are a couple of people--
我在跟奇斯说话
I was talking to Chase.
我看着你不过是想耍你
I was just looking at you to screw with you.
我在沉思
I'm meditating.
在我们看来  像是在睡觉
From where we're standing, it looked like sleeping.
我们找不到她过去的医疗记录
We can't find her old medical records.
你叫醒我就为这事
You woke me up for that?
我们叫醒你因为这无关紧要
We woke you up because it doesn't matter.
爱丽丝拒绝接受其他治疗
Alice is refusing any more treatment.
她不想做手术
She doesn't want the surgery.
她把我们轰出来了
She kicked us out.
她为什么要隐瞒车祸
Why would she lie about the accident?
每个人都会说谎
Everybody lies.
每个人都有说谎的原因
Everybody has a reason.
我听说了
I know.
爱丽丝拒绝做手术
Alice is refusing surgery.
不做手术她几天后就要死了
She'll be dead in a few days without it.
所以我花了四小时时间
Which is why I've spent the last four hours
想找到不经她同意进行手术的合法途径
trying to find a legal way to do it without her permission.
以失败告终  抱歉
Unsuccessfully. I'm sorry.
作为你的男友  我很感激你这么尽心尽力
As your boyfriend, I'm grateful for the effort.
作为你的雇员
As your employee,
我很失望你办事效率低下
I'm disappointed at your ineffectiveness.
她为什么不告诉我们腿上有钉子
Why would she not tell us about the pins in her leg?
因为她想寻死
'cause she wants to die.
就先把自己的腿给搞残废吗
By having her leg ripped off?
她是为了成名前
She wants to punish herself...
在她开始写作前发生的事
for something that happened before she was famous,
在惩罚自己
before she even started to write.
我想答案就在
I think the answer's
她过去的医疗记录里
in her old medical records.
但是那三个又脏又困的混蛋找不到
But dopey, sleazy, and uptighty can't find them.
或许爱丽丝·唐纳只是她的笔名
Maybe Alice Tanner's just her pen name.
你男友真是个白痴
Your boyfriend is an idiot.
我联系下全国档案部
I'll contact the national records archive
识别她腿上螺丝的型号
and run the type of screws in her leg
根据她的血型  年龄确定她的身份
against blood type, age, and anything else I think of.
她可能叫海伦
Her first name could be Helen.
谢谢
Even better.
不劳烦您起来了
Don't bother to get up.
你对杰克的描写
You know, the way you write Jack
栩栩如生
always made him feel real to me.
现在我知道原因了
Now I know why.
因为我是个出色的作家
Because I'm a good writer.
他很厉害  但有些笨拙
He's cool, but he's awkward.
他很聪明  但偶尔犯错
He's brilliant. He makes mistakes.
他很有趣  但有时会玩过火
He's funny, but sometimes he takes it too far.
听起来像个了不起的孩子
Sounds like a great kid.
求求你
Please.
让我一个人呆着
Just leave me alone.
发生车祸时你不是一个人
You weren't alone in the car crash.
还有你的儿子  海伦
Your son was with you, Helen.
你写书是为了让他继续活在你的生命里
The books are your way of keeping him alive.
为什么你就不能让我平静的死去
Why can't you just let me die in peace?
车祸后你一直不得安宁
You haven't been at peace since it happened.
是我害死了他
I killed him.
不  不是你
No, you didn't.
我让他开车
I let him drive.
他只有学习驾照
He only had a learner's permit.
当时在下雨
It was raining.
我应该受到惩罚
I deserve this.
不  不关你的事
No, you don't.
他总有办法让我满足他的一切要求
He could always get me to do what he wanted.
他是我的艺术女神
He's always been my muse.
这倒是有可能
Well, that may be true,
我重新看过
but I've been reviewing
你儿子的验尸报告
your muse's autopsy results.
他不是死于车祸
It wasn't the crash that killed him.
你儿子患有脑动脉瘤
Your son had a brain aneurism.
所以他才会撞车
That's why he crashed.
在车祸前他就死了
He was dead before the impact.
对此你无能为力
There was nothing you could do to save him.
他们应该告诉我这点的
They would have told me.
他们没理由追究真正的死因
They had no reason to dig any deeper.
那是场车祸  但我发现了
It was a car accident. I did.
那很容易被遗漏
It's easy to miss.
你可以看到血块淤积在这里
But you can see the blood buildup here.
你儿子那天怎么样都会死
Your son would have died that day
在公车上  在学校里
on a bus, in school,
或者是坐在床上他都会死
sitting on his bed.
车祸唯一的受害人是你
The only thing the crash is killing is you.
你脖子里的瘘管需要治疗
We need to repair that syrinx in your neck.
他就是我的一切
He was my world.
写作的时候
Writing...
我能感觉到他的存在
I could feel him with me.
那不是我的错  妈妈
It wasn't my fault, mom.
也不是我的错
And it wasn't mine.
她儿子没有脑动脉瘤
Her son didn't have a brain aneurism.
没错
Nope.
她不该让他在雨天开车
She shouldn't have let him drive in the rain.
杰克从来不是个乖小孩
Jack was never very coordinated.
作为你的上司
As your boss,
我反对你欺骗病人
I am opposed to you lying to a patient.
作为你的女友  我很高兴你关心别人
As your girlfriend, I'm glad you care.
我不关心
I don't.
我只想拯救杰克·加农
I just wanted to save Jack Cannon.
我知道你为什么喜欢他了
Well, I can see why you like him.
我开始看你送我的书了
I started reading one of the books you gave me.
我觉得你这话不可信
I find that very hard to believe.
为什么
Why?
因为我不能喜欢你喜欢的东西吗
Because I can't like something you like?
我们没法找到共同点吗
We couldn't possibly have something in common?
因为我没给过你书
Because I lied about giving you the books.
-这样啊  -是啊
- Oh. - Oh.
-威尔森跟你说的  -是的
- Wilson told you. - Yeah.
真是个长舌妇
He's such a gossip.
我不会因为我们喜欢不同的食物
I'm not gonna dump you because we like different food
书籍或音乐甩掉你
or books or music.
换句话说
On the other hand,
如果你觉得我们的关系有问题
I might dump you if you don't talk to me
却不跟我沟通我会甩掉你
when you have a problem with our relationship.
我知道你现在是这么想的
I know you believe that now...
但事实是
but the fact is--
谁在乎共同点
Who cares about common?
共同点多无聊
Common is boring.
随处可见
It's...common!
我喜欢和你在一起  我感觉很好
I like being with you. You make me better.
但愿我也能让你感觉更好
Hopefully, I make you better.
我们之间
What we have is...
就是不同寻常
uncommon.
我也从没这么开心过
And I've never been happier.
让我们单独呆会好吗  克里斯蒂娜
Mind giving us a moment alone, Christina?
我想谢谢你
I'd like to thank you.
很好
Great.
你可以把下一本杰克·加农送给我
You can dedicate the next Jack Cannon to me.
爱莫能助
I can't.
-你还疼吗  -不
- Are you still in pain?  - No.
你医好了我  但帮了我更多
You did everything you said, and more.
我终于能放下包袱了
I can finally move on.
谢谢
Thank you.
怎么说
Move on where?
我想写成人小说了
I want to write books for adults.
杰克怎么办
What about Jack?
你的最后一本书什么都没说
Your last book didn't answer anything.
我结束杰克的故事的方式很完美
The way I ended Jack's story is perfect.
每位读者能根据自己的意愿
Each reader can decide
赋予他之后的人生
what fate they want for him themselves.
你  那太蠢了
You--but that's stupid!
你这样做没道理啊
That doesn't make any sense!
在真实人生中你能得到多少答案
How many answers do you get in real life?
这是本书
This is a book.
必然有开头过程结尾
Books have beginnings, middles, and ends.
你不能就留个悬念
You can't just leave it on a cliffhanger--
哪个作家会这么做
who does that?
抱歉  他的故事结束了
I'm sorry. His story's done.
你说什么都改变不了我的决定
There's really nothing you can say to change my mind.
你儿子
Your son...
能拥有你这样的母亲是他的福气
was very lucky to have you as his mother.
-那  -闭嘴
- That was... - Oh, shut up.